Guide to the William W. Eitel Papers, ca. 1972-1979
Department of Special Collections
William W. Eitel Papers,
ca. 1972-1979
Special Collections M0940
Eitel, William W.
5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Paul Thekan, 1997.
Biography
William W. Eitel joined Heinz & Kaufman in 1929; he was manager of the tube manufacturing department for five years. He was a co-founder of Eitel-McCollough Inc. (EIMAC), now a division of Varian Associates. In 1950 Mr. Eitel was awarded the Navy Distinguished Public Service award for contributions to the electron tube art during World War II. January 1, 1953, he received the grade of Fellow in The Institute of Radio Engineers and was a licensed Professional Engineer in the State of California. Mr. Eitel was a member of the board of trustees of the Foundation for Nutrition and Stress Research; Chairman of the Board of OSCAR, Inc., a satellite company, and was the owner and operator of the Sutro Ranch and Laboratory in Dayton, Nevada.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the papers of William W. Eitel, co-founder of Eitel-McCollough, Inc. and a distinguished engineer. Included are papers depicting the 1970's battle between private Ham Radio operators and the Federal Government over radio wave rights, his involvement with several technical firms and Ham Radio organizations, and personal correspondence with many friends and associates. The collection mainly contains documents regarding Mr. Eitel from 1972-1978.
Access Terms
Eitel-McCullough, Inc.; Eimac Division of Varian, Inc.; Electronic industries.; Science--History.
Container List
- ARRL/FCC Report 7/9/73 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ARRL Report 1/15/74 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ARRL & the space program 5/7/75 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ARRL Foundation letters 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- ARRL (Huntoon, Kelleher, Cotterell, Dennison, etc.) 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- ARRL and amateur radio 1973-76 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- ARRL Board of Directors 1972-73 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- ARRL Pacific division 1972-76 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Wical/Stilwell Campaign 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Booth, Robert M. Jr. 1972-76 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Chapman, Robert 1972-74 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Clark, Victor 1972-76 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Compton, Charles 1972-74 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Dannals, Harry 1974-76 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Dannals, Harry 1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Dannals, Harry 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Kelleher, Jack 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Huber, Louis 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Huntoon, John 1973-74 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Price, Larry 1973-76 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Shima, Larry 1972-76 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Waters, Don 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Project OSCAR 1972-73 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- OSCAR 7 Satellite 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- OSCAR Executive Committee 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Biographies: Root, Carter, Hoover Jr. Eitel, Walker Not Dated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- A Typical Day at the Sutro Ranch 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Spirit of '76/ OSCAR Satellite 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Project OSCAR (Spirit of '76) 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Vincent, Ray 1972-74 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Eitel, Bill (DC Trip Report) 3/72 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Diagnostic Data, Inc. (DDI) 1968-76 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Market Outlook 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Address and Phone Number List Not Dated (Box 3, Folder 14)
- ARRL Correspondence 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence 1977-78 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Letters to Senators 1977-78 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Anderson, Dexter 6/10/77 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Booth, Bob 4/21/78 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Breeding, Chuck 10/4/77 6/6/77 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Clark, Victor C. 5/29/77 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Cotterell, Charles M. 1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Davidoff, Martin (AMSAT) 2/2/77 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Davis, Tom 6/10/77 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Collins, Arthur A. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Draft of Fundraising Letter 2/9/77 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Guatemala 1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Erickson, Ero 8/10/77 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Expense Report 6/17/77 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Fogetti, Howard 2/16/77 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Green, Wayne 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Gartsman, Harry 8/4/77 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Blank Graph Paper Not Dated (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Ham Radio 1/26/77 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Hatherell, George 1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Hesler, Ron Jr. 2/2-2/5/78 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Holsen, Paul 6/10/77 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Hoover, Herbert III 5/3/78 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Houghton, David 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Hurd, Pete 1977-78 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Hunsaker, George L. 2/14/77 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Johnson, John (FCC) 2/10/77 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Joy, Fred L. 2/10/77 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Klien, Perry (AMSAT) 1977-78 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Koyle, Myron R. 2/15/77 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Majerus, Florence 5/26/77 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Mallory, Col. R.R. AUS Ret. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Martin, John 3/27/77 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Martin, Col. Robert G. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Meyer, Armin 10/17/77 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Meyer, Stuart 1977 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Milius, Gay Jr. 4/4/77 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Millen, James 6/9/77 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Mode Amateur Radio Station Not Dated (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Perrine, George E. 1977 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Purinton, Richard M. 10/77 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- QCWA Convention 7/31/77 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Rider, John F. 10/10/77 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Robinson, R.H. 6/15/77 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Shear, Herbert Jr. 6/77 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Smith, Ether 6/7/77 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Smith, Howard K. (ABC News) 4/45/77 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Stoll, Dr. E.D., K2TO 6/2/77 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Summer, Dave 7/28/76 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Talley, David 1977 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Target Publishers 10/12/77 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Walker, Prose 12/21/77 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- White, Robert 6/24/77 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Noble, Armond 3/15/77 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Five Star Club 10/77 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- ARRL Foundation 1975-76 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- GWARC 3/25/76 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- ARS Position- WARC '79 2/17/76 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- FCC- Higgenbotham, Johnson, Wiley, etc. 1975 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- ARRL 1975/76 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- ARRLF Resignation 5/15/76 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Hoover-Dannals Letter 1/7/76 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- ARRL Foundation 1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Telegraph Key with a Memory 7/63 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- V Beam Antenna 2/1/76 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- RSGB Bulletin Radio Communication 2/11/75 (re:11/75) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Hoover Letter (Hurd & Klien) 1/24/76 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Comments- ARRL Board Meeting 1/21/76 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Pacific Division Organization Plan 1/31/76 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Comments- HF/VHF/UHL Allocation 12/9/75 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- WARC Foundation- Satellite Plan 1/21/76 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Contributions of the AMSAT Program 2/20/76 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Tiffany Letter 1/23/76 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Bill Ham Activities 1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Discussion with Cart Smith 6/21/76 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Rain Static 2/1/75 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Bill Ham Activities 1975 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- ARRL Agency Relationship Chart 2/16/75 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- ARRLF Donations 4/26/76 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Integrated Mode Radio Station 1976 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Activity Chart 12/21/75 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Worldradio- Ero Erickson 7/75 & 4/76 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Executive Committee Meeting 1/76 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Five Star Award Club 1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- WARC 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Sutro Ranch 1968-75 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Walker, A. Prose 1969-77 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Business Cards & Postcards Not Dated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Bill Eitel, Ham Activities 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- AMSAT 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- AMSAT (Klien, Daniels) 1972-75 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Dear OM Letter 2/24/75 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- VP 2 VL Log 11/12-15/72 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Bill Eitel, Ham Activities 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Bill Eitel, Ham Activities 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Bill Eitel, Ham Activities 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- ARS Conflict/ FCC Electronic News Article 2/25/73 / Not Dated (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Dear om 1,2,3 3/12-14/73 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Oscillator Reports 10/31 & 12/33 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Tape Correspondence 1960-74 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Barsody, Commander B. Frank 5-6/75 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- CW & Five Star 8/29/74 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Five Star Club Award Master 1974 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Col. Clair Foster 7/20/72 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Goldwater, Barry 1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- HK255 Gammatron (photos) 1/22/75 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Hoover Letter to Clark 10/24/74 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- HR Report (Jim Fisk) 5-6/74 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Huntley, Gred W6RNC 1/29/75 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- McMahon Report 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Martin, Ron 1972-76 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Maxwell, James 1974 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- NCDXF 1974-76 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Tanny, Armand WA6NMY 1/31/75 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Twiggy (Ed Biro K6NB) 1-2/75 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Walton, Bob 1973-74 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- WARC-79/WG/AM 4/9/75 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- WARC Proposition 3/8/74 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- White, R.F. (Bob) W6PY 1/29/75 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Windle, W.H. FOC 1974-75 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Amateur Satellite Service Committee 1972-76 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Amateur Radio Space Communication Program- ASSC-AMSAT-OSCAR 10/12/72 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- OSCAR, Inc. 1973 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Formation of ARRL-ISRU Space Committee 5/14/72 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Goals of ARRL- ISRU Space Committee 5/14/72 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Charts- OSCAR, ARRL 1973-75 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Docket No. 19852 10/25/73 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Docket No. 20282 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Hoover, Tete "Herb Hoover Memorial" 1972-76 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Lievsay, Claude Jr. 1973 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- McQuatters, Earl 6/14/72 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Nose, Katashi 1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Okeeffee, Dr. Vincent 8/29/72 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Outline of OSTG 5/5/72 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Outline- Purpose of 5/18/72 Meeting (OSTG) 5/18/72 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- OSTG Masters 5/14/72 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Success Story 1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Film: Success Story (16mm negative and soundtrack) 12/15/85 (Box 10, Folder 2)